<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Eddie Abbondanzio</title>
    <link>https://EddieAbb95.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Eddie Abbondanzio</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 31 Mar 2018 15:22:42 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://EddieAbb95.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>No Mans Blocks - 3/31 Update</title>
      <link>https://EddieAbb95.github.io/post/nomansblocks/3-31-18-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Mar 2018 15:22:42 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://EddieAbb95.github.io/post/nomansblocks/3-31-18-update/</guid>
      <description>Stepping back into Networking These past few months I&amp;rsquo;ve been on a tangent that wasn&amp;rsquo;t exactly planned. Diving head first into networking code, and attempting to refactor the voxel engine to support it really burnt me out. During this break I&amp;rsquo;ve been focusing on the core voxel engine itself. I decided to take the time to really spruce up the voxel engine and add in some much needed features. While I can&amp;rsquo;t exactly remember every change some of the key ones are:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Object Pooling in Unity</title>
      <link>https://EddieAbb95.github.io/post/unity/object-pool/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Mar 2018 10:06:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://EddieAbb95.github.io/post/unity/object-pool/</guid>
      <description>GameObject.Instantiate() is Expensive Creating new gameobjects during runtime can be a costly operation. Multiple this action by 10 or more times in a single frame and you&amp;rsquo;ll notice a slight hiccup in FPS. One option to counter this is by taking advantage of object pooling. Object pooling is when a collection of inactive gameobjects is kept on standby. When the game needs a new object it can call upon the pool to let it use one of the objects in it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Greedy Meshing for Voxels</title>
      <link>https://EddieAbb95.github.io/post/voxel/greedy-mesh/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Mar 2018 10:06:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://EddieAbb95.github.io/post/voxel/greedy-mesh/</guid>
      <description>What is Greedy Meshing? Anyone who has spent some time working with voxels will have heard of the term &amp;lsquo;Greedy Meshing&amp;rsquo; at some point. If your new to the concept check out this article written by Mikola Lysenko. It&amp;rsquo;s probably the most popular (and if not best) article out there regarding voxel mesh generation.
However if your like me, your probably looking for a simpler explanation and perhaps some source code to really get the ball rolling, and improve your understanding.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New site, who this?</title>
      <link>https://EddieAbb95.github.io/post/misc/first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Mar 2018 10:06:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://EddieAbb95.github.io/post/misc/first-post/</guid>
      <description>Welcome! If your reading this, it means you&amp;rsquo;ve found my new website. It&amp;rsquo;s still in it&amp;rsquo;s early stages so it may seem quite primitive. It&amp;rsquo;s powered via Hugo, and while I may have a decent grasp of HTML/CSS/JS, Go is a whole new concept.
In the following weeks I&amp;rsquo;ll work on dialing things in and at the same time post progresss about my various projects I&amp;rsquo;m working on.
What is this blog about?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>https://EddieAbb95.github.io/page/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://EddieAbb95.github.io/page/about/</guid>
      <description>Welcome! My name is Eddie Abbondanzio, and you&amp;rsquo;ve managed to find my site. This page is currently under construction but come back soon.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>