<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Eddie Abbondanzio</title>
    <link>https://eddieabbondanz.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Eddie Abbondanzio</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 16 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://eddieabbondanz.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Detailing Arsenal</title>
      <link>https://eddieabbondanz.io/app/detailingarsenal/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eddieabbondanz.io/app/detailingarsenal/</guid>
      <description>Detailing Arsenal is a SaaS (software as a service) for managing and scheduling appointments for auto detailers. Users can create, update, or delete appointments, along with the ability to view stats about time, services, and revenue.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Updog</title>
      <link>https://eddieabbondanz.io/app/updog/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eddieabbondanz.io/app/updog/</guid>
      <description>Updog was a Reddit clone where users could share links, and create text posts. Users could submit comments to posts, or reply to other comments. A voting system was implemented to allow users to upvote or downvote posts they liked or disliked.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mechanic Log</title>
      <link>https://eddieabbondanz.io/app/mechaniclog/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eddieabbondanz.io/app/mechaniclog/</guid>
      <description>Mechanic Log was a web app where users could log repairs and maintenance performed on their vehicle(s). Users could also track fuel mileage to see how much they spent in fuel, gallons consumed, and lifetime MPG.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clap Button</title>
      <link>https://eddieabbondanz.io/app/clapbutton/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eddieabbondanz.io/app/clapbutton/</guid>
      <description>Clap Button was a SaaS that offered a Medium like clap button widget for blogs. The widget allowed readers to share their appreciation for a blog post by clicking on it to &amp;ldquo;clap&amp;rdquo; 1 to 50 times.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rust Repair Part 13: Replacing the Passenger Inner Rocker To Prep for 2x6 Rockers</title>
      <link>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/xj/unibody-rust-repair-part-13/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/xj/unibody-rust-repair-part-13/</guid>
      <description>With all this metal laying around it was about time I started putting it to use. 
While the 2x6 rocker mod for XJ isn&amp;rsquo;t uncommon by any means, I&amp;rsquo;m planning on taking a slightly different approach in how I tie them into the unibody.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rust Repair Part 12: Welding in the New Passenger Drip Rail</title>
      <link>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/xj/unibody-rust-repair-part-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/xj/unibody-rust-repair-part-12/</guid>
      <description>My new metal brake finally arrived. 
Before settling on the Woodward Fab Boss 16, I spent several hours researching metal brakes and looked at a ton of different models across various manufacturers such as Baileigh, Tennsmith, Grizzly, JET, Eastwood, and Enco.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rust Repair Part 11: Finishing What I Started</title>
      <link>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/xj/unibody-rust-repair-part-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/xj/unibody-rust-repair-part-11/</guid>
      <description>Just shy of two years ago now, I embarked on the largest rust repair job I&amp;rsquo;ve ever done on my XJ. It took me several months, but I was able to replace the entire rear cargo floor including the crossmembers, gas tank bracing, and unibody frame rails along with welding in rear frame stiffeners over my newly made frame rails.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Electrical Gremlins, a Blown Clutch, and a Massive Oil Leak</title>
      <link>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/88-integra/electrical-gremlins-and-a-blown-clutch/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/88-integra/electrical-gremlins-and-a-blown-clutch/</guid>
      <description>Having driven over 2,500 miles and raced in 2 auto cross events, the Integra has had a few issues pop up along the way, but is still holding strong.
For what it&amp;rsquo;s worth though, the car&amp;rsquo;s never left me stranded and even when the clutch failed I was still able to limp it home.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Back on the Road After a Decade</title>
      <link>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/88-integra/back-on-the-road-after-a-decade/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/88-integra/back-on-the-road-after-a-decade/</guid>
      <description>Wrapping up a project isn&amp;rsquo;t always the funnest. The &amp;ldquo;last 10%&amp;rdquo; tends to take up significantly more time than anticipated because it involves addressing all the difficult parts that you&amp;rsquo;ve been putting off.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fabricating a 304 Stainless Catback Exhaust</title>
      <link>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/88-integra/304-stainless-catback/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/88-integra/304-stainless-catback/</guid>
      <description>The exhaust on my new to me 88 Integra was beyond saving with several holes in the resonator and the muffler having turned questionably brittle. As this is suppose to be a summer daily driver that&amp;rsquo;s pleasant to drive I decided to splurge and build a stainless exhaust setup to save my ears and retain my sanity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Replacing a D16A1 Headgasket and Timing Belt</title>
      <link>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/88-integra/d16a1-headgasket-and-timing-belt/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/88-integra/d16a1-headgasket-and-timing-belt/</guid>
      <description>With the headgasket and timing belt swap fully completed it feels like the rest of this project will be a piece of cake. Fabricating a custom exhaust is the last major task on the list and I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to it because that means I have an excuse to break out my welder.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Refreshing the Suspension</title>
      <link>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/88-integra/refreshing-the-suspension/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/88-integra/refreshing-the-suspension/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s been just under a month since my last post about fixing up this Integra and I&amp;rsquo;ve made a ton of progress. I&amp;rsquo;ve successfully completed replacing most of the suspension including all four shocks, outer tie rods, ball joints, sway bar bushings, cv axles, and front lower control arms.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fixing the Brakes</title>
      <link>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/88-integra/fixing-the-brakes-and-more/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/88-integra/fixing-the-brakes-and-more/</guid>
      <description>With February quickly approaching, I&amp;rsquo;m starting to feel like I&amp;rsquo;m running short on time to get my recently acquired 1988 Acura Integra road ready. My current goal is to have this vehicle on the road for spring and it&amp;rsquo;s been harder to make progress on it than anticipated.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The First Start</title>
      <link>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/88-integra/first-start-in-8-years/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/88-integra/first-start-in-8-years/</guid>
      <description>Last weekend I had the opportunity to purchase a bone stock 1988 Acura Integra from it&amp;rsquo;s original owner. The previous owner is a family friend of ours and has had this sitting in his garage for over 9 years now.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fabricating a New Rear Bumper</title>
      <link>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/xj/fabricating-a-rear-bumper/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/xj/fabricating-a-rear-bumper/</guid>
      <description>Preface I&amp;rsquo;ve been driving my Jeep around for almost 6 months now with no rear bumper. I know, I know, not the safest choice but I don&amp;rsquo;t drive far. Why? Because 6 months ago I wrapped up an extensive rust repair project on my XJ where I cut out and replaced the entire rear floor along with the unibody frame rails and crossmembers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Replacing a Saggy Headliner</title>
      <link>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/xj/replacing-a-saggy-headliner/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/xj/replacing-a-saggy-headliner/</guid>
      <description>Delaying the Inevitable When it comes to my cars, I like to bunch up my repairs / mods into batches where I&amp;rsquo;ll focus on one small sub-category of tasks before moving onto the next.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Installing a Gentex 177 Auto Dimming Rear View Mirror</title>
      <link>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/xj/gentex-177-mirror-install/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/xj/gentex-177-mirror-install/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s hard to explain, but driving a car at night that has an auto dimming rear view mirror is a real treat. It&amp;rsquo;s one of those things that you&amp;rsquo;ll never notice when it&amp;rsquo;s working, but as soon as you don&amp;rsquo;t have it you&amp;rsquo;ll notice its absence immediately.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Abusing For Loops In C# For Job Security</title>
      <link>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/c-sharp/abusing-for-loops-for-job-security/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/c-sharp/abusing-for-loops-for-job-security/</guid>
      <description>Everyone knows good code is easy to maintain, but that also means anyone can maintain it. That&amp;rsquo;s no bueno for the individual developer who wants a little job security. Writing overly complex code that nobody else can maintain let alone read, will ensure your company holds onto you, and will give you more bargaining power come raise time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rust Repair Part 10: The Finishing Touches</title>
      <link>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/xj/unibody-rust-repair-part-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/xj/unibody-rust-repair-part-10/</guid>
      <description>The epoxy primer I used on the underside of my repairs is some pretty good stuff, but I wanted just a hair more protection down there. And after all can you really say you did a rust repair job on your Jeep if bedliner wasn&amp;rsquo;t involved?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rust Repair Part 9: Closing Up The Floor</title>
      <link>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/xj/unibody-rust-repair-part-9/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/xj/unibody-rust-repair-part-9/</guid>
      <description>The least exciting portion of this project by far was closing up the two holes left in the floor directly below where the rear seat goes. I initally cut these holes in the floor way back at the beginning of the project because I needed to remove the original frame rails.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rust Repair Part 8: Welding on Frame Stiffeners</title>
      <link>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/xj/unibody-rust-repair-part-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/xj/unibody-rust-repair-part-8/</guid>
      <description>One of my biggest concerns about my custom fabricated frame rails was the vertical welds joining the frame sections. Vertical welds like those are a big no no when it comes to frames because they&amp;rsquo;re especially prone to failing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rust Repair Part 7: A New Fuel Neck Housing And Making Cut N Fold Panels</title>
      <link>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/xj/unibody-rust-repair-part-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/xj/unibody-rust-repair-part-7/</guid>
      <description>The Fuel Neck Housing I&amp;rsquo;ve been ignoring the gaping hole around where the fuel neck passes through the interior to travel down towards the gas tank. I had a feeling it&amp;rsquo;d be easy to fix so I never put much thought into it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rust Repair Part 6: Turning A Patch Panel Into A New Cargo Floor Pan</title>
      <link>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/xj/unibody-rust-repair-part-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/xj/unibody-rust-repair-part-6/</guid>
      <description>Building Out The Cargo Floor I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to try to salvage the original cargo area floor from my Jeep. It had rusted through in several spots, and I kinda chopped it up into several pieces because I only removed bits of it as a time when I was fabricating the new frame rails.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rust Repair Part 5: Designing A Custom Gas Tank Cradle</title>
      <link>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/xj/unibody-rust-repair-part-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/xj/unibody-rust-repair-part-5/</guid>
      <description>Directly below the floor of the XJ in the cargo area sits the gas tank. Tucked tight between the frame rails it rests a mere 1/2&amp;quot; from the floor. The mount for the gas tank is also what braces the floor in the cargo area.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rust Repair Part 4: Hooking Up The Suspension</title>
      <link>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/xj/unibody-rust-repair-part-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/xj/unibody-rust-repair-part-4/</guid>
      <description>With the frame squared away I needed something that I could mount up the suspension to. The only thing holding in the rear axle at this point was the rear driveshaft and the front mounts of the leaf springs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rust Repair Part 3: Déjà Vu Replacing the Driver Frame Rail</title>
      <link>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/xj/unibody-rust-repair-part-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/xj/unibody-rust-repair-part-3/</guid>
      <description>The driver side frame rail was in far worse shape than the passenger side on my XJ. I opted to replace the passenger side first since there&amp;rsquo;s a little less going on on that side.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rust Repair Part 2: Bending a New Passenger Frame Rail</title>
      <link>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/xj/unibody-rust-repair-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/xj/unibody-rust-repair-part-2/</guid>
      <description>Using a metal brake to bend up new frame rails wasn&amp;rsquo;t my plan A. Nor was it plan B. It was actually plan C. I was trying to fix my Jeep on the cheap because this repair wasn&amp;rsquo;t suppose to happen till spring.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rust Repair Part 1: Fabricating A New Rear Crossmember</title>
      <link>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/xj/unibody-rust-repair-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/xj/unibody-rust-repair-part-1/</guid>
      <description>Background I like to joke and say that anyone else would have sent my XJ to the junkyard.
My Cherokee is rusty, has a laundry list of issues, gets 17 MPG on the good days, and is literally a brick on wheels.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dana 30 Front Axle Rebuild</title>
      <link>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/xj/dana-30-rebuild/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/xj/dana-30-rebuild/</guid>
      <description>The front axle of my Cherokee has been in desperate need of some attention for quite awhile. Just about every component on it was worn to the point of needing to be replaced and the axle housing itself had built up some pretty intense rust.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TypeScript - Await Promise.All() And Get The Results</title>
      <link>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/typescript/await-promise-all/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/typescript/await-promise-all/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m a big fan of the async await syntax in ES2017. In my opionion it just feels a lot more natural than and then and then and then&amp;hellip;. I digress. I&amp;rsquo;ll keep this one short.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unity - LiteNetLib&#39;s Delivery Methods</title>
      <link>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/unity/litenetlib-delivery-methods/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2019 21:31:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/unity/litenetlib-delivery-methods/</guid>
      <description>While LiteNetLib may run on UDP (User Datagram Protocol) which is an unreliable network protocol, LiteNetLib offers multiple delivery methods, some of which even offer &amp;ldquo;reliability&amp;rdquo;. Reliability is in quotes because when latency is high the chance of a packet being dropped is greater than 0 (although still fairly rare).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unity - How to Send Data With LiteNetLib</title>
      <link>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/unity/litenetlib-sending-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2019 19:04:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/unity/litenetlib-sending-data/</guid>
      <description>Continuing off the previous post about how to build a basic server / client set up with LiteNetLib it&amp;rsquo;s time to talk about sending data. Because, well, a network set up that doesn&amp;rsquo;t actually send any data is kind of useless.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unity - How to Create a Basic Server / Client With LiteNetLib</title>
      <link>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/unity/litenetlib-basic-server-client/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2019 06:10:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/unity/litenetlib-basic-server-client/</guid>
      <description>LiteNetLib already provides a good example for creating a basic server / client set up in their documents, but if we want to use it with Unity there&amp;rsquo;s a few extra steps we&amp;rsquo;ll need to take.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unity - How to Set Up LiteNetLib</title>
      <link>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/unity/litenetlib-setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2019 21:01:01 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/unity/litenetlib-setup/</guid>
      <description>TL;DR Download the most recent stable release source code zip and copy the /LiteNetLib folder to the Plugins folder in your Unity project.
LiteNetLib is an UDP networking library that can be used for building multiplayer games with Unity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ASP.NET Core - Claims Based Authentication: Claims vs Identities vs Principals</title>
      <link>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/aspnet/claims-based-authentication-claims-identities-principals/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2019 14:50:42 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/aspnet/claims-based-authentication-claims-identities-principals/</guid>
      <description>With the rise of ASP.NET Core over ASP.NET 4.x, the built in authentication has undergone a shift from role-based access control (RBAC) to claim-based access control (CBAC). The most notable change is the User property on HttpContext is now of type ClaimsPrincipal instead of IPrincipal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ASP.NET Core - Inversion of Control Container</title>
      <link>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/aspnet/inversion-of-control-containers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Jun 2019 14:50:42 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/aspnet/inversion-of-control-containers/</guid>
      <description>ASP.NET Core supports dependency injection directly out of the box. For Web APIs this is useful for automatically resolving dependencies needed by controllers, or if you&amp;rsquo;re a fan of Uncle Bob&amp;rsquo;s Clean Architecture it can be used to inject external dependencies such as the database into the inner layers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WorkStation - Goodbye Windows</title>
      <link>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/laptop/kubuntu/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/laptop/kubuntu/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been using Windows for as long as I can remember. Back when Windows 2000 was a big deal I remember using it to play Space Cadet pinball although I was never very good at it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WorkStation - More RAM</title>
      <link>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/laptop/more-ram/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Feb 2019 21:17:42 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/laptop/more-ram/</guid>
      <description>Mo&#39; RAM, Mo&#39; Problems I use my laptop for a ton of software development. I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on launching a SaaS and I often need to have a development build of the backend running along with the frontend.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>XJ Build - 02/03/19</title>
      <link>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/xj/19-02-03/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Feb 2019 17:28:42 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/xj/19-02-03/</guid>
      <description>The Cherokee strikes again. A couple weeks back when my exhaust snapped just before the catalytic converter I noticed my muffler had a minor leak. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t anything major and wasn&amp;rsquo;t loud so I figured I could probably just run it till spring and deal with it when it was warmer out.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TypeScript - Interpolated Strings</title>
      <link>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/typescript/interpolated-strings/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 16:52:42 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/typescript/interpolated-strings/</guid>
      <description>Coming from the .NET world String.Format() was by far my most used function for generating user readable error / log messages. After jumping over to TypeScript, I was bummed to learn that no similar function existed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HTTP Status Codes For a RESTful API</title>
      <link>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/http/status-codes-for-rest/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2019 18:29:29 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/http/status-codes-for-rest/</guid>
      <description>Intro Hyper Text Transfer Protocol (HTTP) powers the web. It&amp;rsquo;s the silent work horse used to carry data between servers and clients, and is the reason why all URLs start with HTTP, or HTTPS.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>XJ Build - 01/26/19</title>
      <link>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/xj/19-01-26/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Jan 2019 16:51:42 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/xj/19-01-26/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve honestly been very lucky with my Jeep. My previous daily driver was a 2009 Subaru Legacy, and while it may have been excellent in the snow it had a very high cost of ownership.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HTTP Cookies</title>
      <link>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/http/cookies/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Jan 2019 18:37:24 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/http/cookies/</guid>
      <description>What Are They? HTTP cookies are small bits of text that are included with each HTTP request made from a user&amp;rsquo;s web browser to web servers. HTTP is a stateless protocol which means each requests is treated as a unique command, and no state data is maintained.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TypeScript - Events</title>
      <link>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/typescript/events/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jan 2019 18:37:24 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/typescript/events/</guid>
      <description>Intro If you were expecting a phone call from a friend, you (hopefully) wouldn&amp;rsquo;t sit by the phone and continuously pick it up to see if your friend was on the other end.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TypeScript - Taking The Magic Out of Magic Strings</title>
      <link>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/typescript/magic-strings/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Jan 2019 09:53:42 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/typescript/magic-strings/</guid>
      <description>What&amp;rsquo;s so Magical About Magic Strings? Magic strings are string literals strewn about a code base that apply some kind of limitation to the code. They can be used to filter valid input, constrain parameters, or control the behavior of code.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TypeScript - How To Set Up A New Project</title>
      <link>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/typescript/setting-up-a-typescript-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Nov 2018 06:57:42 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/typescript/setting-up-a-typescript-project/</guid>
      <description>Summary For beginners TypeScript is like the carrot on the end of the stick, always just out of reach no matter how hard you try. Everyone touts how it&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;JavaScript that scales&amp;rdquo;, and once you use it you&amp;rsquo;ll never go back.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Software Design - Marker Interfaces</title>
      <link>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/software-design/marker-interfaces/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Nov 2018 05:12:42 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/software-design/marker-interfaces/</guid>
      <description>What Are They? A marker interface is an empty interface (no methods or properties) that is used to identify classes that implement it belong to a special group. Some might argue that this is a code smell, but in certain situations they can be the best solution for constraining types.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Software Design - Magic Numbers</title>
      <link>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/software-design/magic-numbers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Oct 2018 19:16:42 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/software-design/magic-numbers/</guid>
      <description>What Are They? Magic numbers are numbers in code that appear to be arbitrary, but actually serve a purpose. They are commonly described as an anti-pattern as they diminish code quality, and are &amp;ldquo;referred to as breaking one of the oldest rules of programming, dating back to the COBOL, FORTRAN and PL/1 manuals of the 1960s&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>XJ Build - 10/26/18</title>
      <link>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/xj/18-10-26/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Oct 2018 16:51:42 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/xj/18-10-26/</guid>
      <description>Finishing Up With winter approaching fast, and my Civic only having summer tires I needed to hurry up and finish the Cherokee. The Civic was also suffering from a stuck open thermostat that ensured the engine temperature never reached operating temp, and my heat was always cold.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>XJ Build - 10/21/18</title>
      <link>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/xj/18-10-21/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Oct 2018 16:51:42 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/xj/18-10-21/</guid>
      <description>Patching Holes This post is a continuation of the mini series about restoring my old XJ cherokee. In the previous post I talked about cutting out and welding in a new rocker panel.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Software Design - Dependency Injection and Inversion</title>
      <link>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/software-design/dependency-injection/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Oct 2018 06:34:42 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/software-design/dependency-injection/</guid>
      <description>What are they? While it may seem like nothing more than buzz words, dependency injection is a well known principle. In fact, you&amp;rsquo;ve likely used it yourself in the past and just didn&amp;rsquo;t know the technique had a name.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Software Design - Unit Tests vs Integration Tests</title>
      <link>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/software-design/unit-tests-vs-integration-tests/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Oct 2018 05:16:42 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/software-design/unit-tests-vs-integration-tests/</guid>
      <description>Preface Unit tests and integration tests are designed to serve two different purposes. They are not meant to substitute each other, and each type has a specific focus. However, developers tend to struggle to determine the border that seperates unit tests and integration tests as there is no set hard limit on either one.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>No Mans Blocks - 10/13/2018</title>
      <link>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/nomansblocks/18-10-13/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Oct 2018 15:05:42 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/nomansblocks/18-10-13/</guid>
      <description>Where I&amp;rsquo;ve Been, and Where I&amp;rsquo;m Heading I took somewhat of an unplanned hiatus from working on No Mans Blocks. Initially, I took a break because I wanted to pursue writing a server for a Reddit clone.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Software Design - Validator Pattern</title>
      <link>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/software-design/validator-pattern/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Oct 2018 05:16:42 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/software-design/validator-pattern/</guid>
      <description>Validating Objects Based on Context It&amp;rsquo;s quite typical for a Domain Driven Design (DDD) project to need validation for it&amp;rsquo;s domain models. While it may be sufficient to solve this by adding an IsValid() method to each model, this can cause confusion for the developer by cluttering the model class, and/or by requiring the IsValid() method to be generalized that it covers a large range of validation rules for any situation that may arise.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>XJ Build - 10/8/18</title>
      <link>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/xj/18-10-08/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Oct 2018 17:22:42 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/xj/18-10-08/</guid>
      <description>Passenger side rocker replacement This post is the second part in my mini-series of restoring my old xj cherokee. If your interested, check out my attempt at saving the rusty roof.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Work Station 2.0</title>
      <link>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/misc/desk2-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Oct 2018 15:22:42 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/misc/desk2-0/</guid>
      <description>Going all out This post is a successor to my first attempt at [building a standing desk] ( /post/misc/desk/). Back during college when I built my first desk I didn&amp;rsquo;t have much of a budget since it was a spur of the moment decision.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>XJ Build - 9/03/18</title>
      <link>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/xj/18-09-03/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Sep 2018 12:57:42 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/xj/18-09-03/</guid>
      <description>Repainting the Cherokee&amp;rsquo;s roof I&amp;rsquo;m a big fan of older vehicles. I just love the simplicity of them and how easy they are to work on them. Plus the cost of parts really can&amp;rsquo;t be beat.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Civic Build - 6/23/18</title>
      <link>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/civic/18-06-23/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Jun 2018 12:57:42 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/civic/18-06-23/</guid>
      <description>Ten months of work finally pays off I enjoy working on my own vehicles but by far the best part is finishing up. While it took longer than I hoped, and the deadlines I kept setting for myself came and went I can say it was worth the wait.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Civic Build - 6/9/18</title>
      <link>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/civic/18-06-09/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Jun 2018 12:57:42 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/civic/18-06-09/</guid>
      <description>Getting ready for the test drive While the car may not be on the road yet, it&amp;rsquo;s come quite a bit closer to getting there. Lately I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on fixing everything that was sub-optimally done previously by me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>No Mans Blocks - 6/4/18</title>
      <link>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/nomansblocks/18-06-04/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jun 2018 20:05:42 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/nomansblocks/18-06-04/</guid>
      <description>Creating Time (literally!) I have a knack for forgetting what I&amp;rsquo;ve managed to accomplish on the game during the week. To try to overcome this so I have updates I can post on it, I&amp;rsquo;ve started writing down each accomplishment on a sticky note.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Civic Build - 5/20/18</title>
      <link>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/civic/18-05-20/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 May 2018 12:57:42 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/civic/18-05-20/</guid>
      <description>Finishing things up With the weather warming up it&amp;rsquo;s been making me miss the civic quite a bit. While it may not be the fastest car out there I do enjoy riving it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>C# Threadable Queue</title>
      <link>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/c-sharp/threadable-queue/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 May 2018 19:04:42 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/c-sharp/threadable-queue/</guid>
      <description>Implementing a Thread-Safe Queue One of the most useful data structures when it comes to multi-threading is the queue. However, queues in c# aren&amp;rsquo;t thread-safe by default. Thankfully it&amp;rsquo;s easy enough to implement your own as we will do today.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>No Mans Blocks - 4/20/18</title>
      <link>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/nomansblocks/18-04-20/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Apr 2018 23:05:42 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/nomansblocks/18-04-20/</guid>
      <description>Playing Around at the Bit Level This weeks adventure has been exploring object serialization. Initially I was using the serializable attribute to convert my objects into byte arrays but for some objects such as the voxel chunks this is far from ideal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Civic Build - 4/15/18</title>
      <link>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/civic/18-04-15/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Apr 2018 20:57:42 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/civic/18-04-15/</guid>
      <description>Connecting the Pieces It&amp;rsquo;s easy to forget just how many parts you&amp;rsquo;ve removed until it comes time to put them all back together. I know I&amp;rsquo;m probably not alone when I say I&amp;rsquo;ve fallen victim to scope creep many times now.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Civic Build - 4/14/18</title>
      <link>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/civic/18-04-14/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Apr 2018 20:40:42 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/civic/18-04-14/</guid>
      <description>Getting Closer. I ran into a few set backs this weekend, and I&amp;rsquo;m a little annoyed but at the same time the civic is really close to being done. I started off by prepping the transmission and engine for being mated together.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Civic Build - 4/12/18</title>
      <link>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/civic/18-04-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Apr 2018 13:13:42 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/civic/18-04-12/</guid>
      <description>Restoring the transmission My girlfriend and I went on a road trip to Vermont to pick up this transmission. Funny enough I wasn&amp;rsquo;t able to find only a transmission so I had to buy a B18b1 engine to get this guy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>No Mans Blocks - 4/8/18</title>
      <link>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/nomansblocks/18-04-08/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Apr 2018 18:25:42 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/nomansblocks/18-04-08/</guid>
      <description>Building Up the Network Logic While this week may not have much to show for it has built a solid foundation for networking. I spent some time refactoring the pre-existing network logic to try to clean things up.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Civic Build - 4/8/18</title>
      <link>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/civic/18-04-08/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Apr 2018 18:04:42 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/civic/18-04-08/</guid>
      <description>New Transmission Mount Installed Progress wise not too much more has been done on the Civic this week. I had to help out my girlfriend put new front brakes + an oil change so I wasn&amp;rsquo;t feeling too motivated after that.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Civic Build - 4/6/18</title>
      <link>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/civic/18-04-06/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Apr 2018 16:22:42 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/civic/18-04-06/</guid>
      <description>Wrapping it up It&amp;rsquo;s funny, you never realize how many things are missing until you try to finish up your project. I spent today going over the motor ensuring I had everything I needed for it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>B-Series Bolt Sizes</title>
      <link>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/honda/b-series-bolts/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Apr 2018 15:22:42 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/honda/b-series-bolts/</guid>
      <description>Trying to find the size of a missing bolt? I&amp;rsquo;m in the middle of swapping a B20B into my 1993 civic, and I had to buy (just about) every bolt / nut on the engine and transmission since I was missing so many.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Civic Build - 4/1/18</title>
      <link>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/civic/18-04-01/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2018 15:22:42 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/civic/18-04-01/</guid>
      <description>I like projects And I&amp;rsquo;m the kind of person that can&amp;rsquo;t leave a car alone. My civic is a 1993 DX hatch that I picked up off a friend of a friend 3 years ago.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Work Station</title>
      <link>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/misc/desk/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2018 15:22:42 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/misc/desk/</guid>
      <description>My Budget Build At my work, I&amp;rsquo;m fortunate enough to have one of those adjustable desks that allow for you to stand or sit while you work. Since I almost always have it in the standing mode I decided to build my own standing desk at home.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Logging to Unity or Console</title>
      <link>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/unity/debug-logging/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Mar 2018 15:56:01 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/unity/debug-logging/</guid>
      <description>Sometimes we want code that can run outside of Unity And that can make things tricky when it comes to writing text to console. Unity has it&amp;rsquo;s own set of methods for writing to it&amp;rsquo;s command console via the Debug class with the most commonly used one being Debug.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>No Mans Blocks - 3/31/18</title>
      <link>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/nomansblocks/18-03-31/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Mar 2018 15:22:42 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/nomansblocks/18-03-31/</guid>
      <description>Stepping back into Networking These past few months I&amp;rsquo;ve been on a tangent that wasn&amp;rsquo;t exactly planned. Diving head first into networking code, and attempting to refactor the voxel engine to support it really burnt me out.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Object Pooling in Unity</title>
      <link>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/unity/object-pool/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Mar 2018 10:06:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/unity/object-pool/</guid>
      <description>GameObject.Instantiate() is Expensive Creating new gameobjects during runtime can be a costly operation. Multiple this action by 10 or more times in a single frame and you&amp;rsquo;ll notice a slight hiccup in FPS.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Greedy Meshing for Vertex Colored Voxels In Unity</title>
      <link>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/voxel/greedy-mesh/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Mar 2018 10:06:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/voxel/greedy-mesh/</guid>
      <description>TL;DR Full algorithm is at the bottom. Classes for Block, Chunk, and MeshData are defined below the intro.
This article goes over how to implement a greedy meshing algorithm for generating optimized meshes for vertex-colored voxels in Unity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Civic Build - 09/07/15</title>
      <link>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/civic/15-09-07/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/civic/15-09-07/</guid>
      <description>Now that I&amp;rsquo;m back at college it&amp;rsquo;s been hard to make progress on the Civic. I do have a slight update to drop as the hood is just about done now.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Civic Build - 08/22/15</title>
      <link>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/civic/15-08-22/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Aug 2015 20:44:42 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/civic/15-08-22/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been quite busy working on the Civic in the past month. I&amp;rsquo;m verfy excited to shared the journey I&amp;rsquo;m embarking on, and can&amp;rsquo;t wait to see how the finished product looks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Civic Build - 07/06/15</title>
      <link>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/civic/15-07-06/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jul 2015 20:44:42 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/civic/15-07-06/</guid>
      <description>The transmission in the Civic was a good deal for the price of $100, but it had a nasty grind anytime you shifted into 3rd gear above 3k RPM. Because of this, and a transmission popping up for sale for $75 bucks I couldn&amp;rsquo;t resist making the switch.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Civic Build - 07/03/15</title>
      <link>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/civic/15-07-03/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jul 2015 19:43:42 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/civic/15-07-03/</guid>
      <description>I don&amp;rsquo;t know why, but I&amp;rsquo;ve always been a fan of Honda. I just love the simplicity, and elegant styling. Sure they may not be the most luxurious cars out there but they are reliable and that&amp;rsquo;s a fact.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Acura Build - 09/09/2014</title>
      <link>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/acura/14-09-09/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/acura/14-09-09/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been fairly quiet since I&amp;rsquo;ve just been enjoying the car. I&amp;rsquo;ve moved up North for college and have decided to sell the RL. There&amp;rsquo;s nothing wrong with it I&amp;rsquo;m just bored of it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Acura Build - 05/25/2014</title>
      <link>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/acura/14-05-25/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/acura/14-05-25/</guid>
      <description>The fog lights were a little too squarish for my taste so I made some custom overlays to give them a slight &amp;ldquo;curve&amp;rdquo;. The grill is also the custom debadged one I made a couple months back.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Acura Build - 05/10/2014</title>
      <link>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/acura/14-05-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/acura/14-05-10/</guid>
      <description>With a stock exhaust the car was fairly quiet. I decided it was time to let the 3.5 V6 under the hood make some noise and ordered a Borla exhaust.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Acura Build - 04/04/2014</title>
      <link>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/acura/14-04-04/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/acura/14-04-04/</guid>
      <description>The RL looks nice but a luxury sedan should really have some tint to it. Initially I planned on doing 35% all around but they shipped me the wrong tint so it ended up with 5% in the rear.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Acura Build - 03/14/2014</title>
      <link>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/acura/14-03-14/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/acura/14-03-14/</guid>
      <description>Made a little more progress on the tablet. I&amp;rsquo;m using a Nexus 7 Gen 2 tablet.
 
I had to open up the tablet to solder in wires to the power button.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Acura Build - 03/04/2014</title>
      <link>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/acura/14-03-04/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/acura/14-03-04/</guid>
      <description>In 2002 the RL came with clear corner tail lights. I&amp;rsquo;ve been envious of the since my 1999 features amber corners but tail lights on Ebay are too expensive.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Acura Build - 01/22/2014</title>
      <link>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/acura/14-01-22/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/acura/14-01-22/</guid>
      <description>For 1999 the RL was pretty advanced. It came fitted with a built in GPS system that was probably pretty slick for it&amp;rsquo;s time. However, it hasn&amp;rsquo;t aged too well and is no longer really useful with out of date maps and it&amp;rsquo;s failing hard drive.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Acura Build - 01/09/2014</title>
      <link>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/acura/14-01-09/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/acura/14-01-09/</guid>
      <description>The projector retrofit is finally coming to an end.

There isn&amp;rsquo;t too much gap between the reflector and shroud which isn&amp;rsquo;t too bad.

The new D2S bulbs also came in.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Acura Build - 01/05/2014</title>
      <link>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/acura/14-01-05/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/acura/14-01-05/</guid>
      <description>I decided to re add the defusers over the blinkers. It looks better in my opinion and feels more OEM.
 
Ran into a slight set back. The caps on the back of the headlights are too shallow and will need some modifications.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Acura Build - 12/30/2013</title>
      <link>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/acura/13-12-30/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/acura/13-12-30/</guid>
      <description>I like doing little things to fix things up. The speaker grills on the car are showing their age so I decided to re upholster them to look new again. Left is original, right is new.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Acura Build - 12/18/2013</title>
      <link>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/acura/13-12-18/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/acura/13-12-18/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to do a projector retrofit. There&amp;rsquo;s nothing wrong with the current headlights I just really like the appeal of the crisp cutoff.

I separated the lense from the headlight house so I could begin to mount things in place.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Acura Build - 12/16/2013</title>
      <link>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/acura/13-12-16/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/acura/13-12-16/</guid>
      <description>I bought my first car off my Grandmother. It&amp;rsquo;s a 1999 Acura 3.5RL in rough condition. I&amp;rsquo;ve owned it for about 3 years now and only done a few small mods to it since.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eddie Abbondanzio</title>
      <link>https://eddieabbondanz.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eddieabbondanz.io/about/</guid>
      <description>My name&amp;rsquo;s Eddie Abbondanzio, and as you&amp;rsquo;ve probably already figured out this is my personal blog. Most of my posts will be technical writeups on projects I&amp;rsquo;ve completed but occasionally I&amp;rsquo;ll thrown in some humorous content.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
