<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Jeep on Eddie Abbondanzio</title>
    <link>https://EddieAbbondanzio.github.io/categories/jeep/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Jeep on Eddie Abbondanzio</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2019. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 03 Feb 2019 17:28:42 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://EddieAbbondanzio.github.io/categories/jeep/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Cherokee Build - 02/03/19</title>
      <link>https://EddieAbbondanzio.github.io/post/cherokee/19-02-03/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Feb 2019 17:28:42 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://EddieAbbondanzio.github.io/post/cherokee/19-02-03/</guid>
      <description>The Cherokee strikes again. A couple weeks back when my exhaust snapped just before the catalytic converter I noticed my muffler had a minor leak. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t anything major and wasn&amp;rsquo;t loud so I figured I could probably just run it till spring and deal with it when it was warmer out.
The Jeep had other plans though as the leak grew in size, and became extremely obnoxious. Due to the internals of the muffler rusting and coming loose, the muffler developed a horrendous rattle that sounded like a trumpet blasting a low note when at 2300RPM.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cherokee Build - 01/26/19</title>
      <link>https://EddieAbbondanzio.github.io/post/cherokee/19-01-26/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Jan 2019 16:51:42 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://EddieAbbondanzio.github.io/post/cherokee/19-01-26/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve honestly been very lucky with my Jeep. My previous daily driver was a 2009 Subaru Legacy, and while it may have been excellent in the snow it had a very high cost of ownership. I figured out that it was costing me on average $100 in maintenance per 1000 miles travelled. It may sound silly to have sold the Subaru and bought a Jeep that was 9 years older but I have zero regrets doing so.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cherokee Build - 10/26/18</title>
      <link>https://EddieAbbondanzio.github.io/post/cherokee/18-10-26/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Oct 2018 16:51:42 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://EddieAbbondanzio.github.io/post/cherokee/18-10-26/</guid>
      <description>Finishing Up With winter approaching fast, and my Civic only having summer tires I needed to hurry up and finish the Cherokee. The Civic was also suffering from a stuck open thermostat that ensured the engine temperature never reached operating temp, and my heat was always cold.
The funny thing is, when I was preparing to drop the B20B engine into the Civic I clearly remember thinking how pointless it would be to replace the thermostat.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cherokee Build - 10/21/18</title>
      <link>https://EddieAbbondanzio.github.io/post/cherokee/18-10-21/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Oct 2018 16:51:42 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://EddieAbbondanzio.github.io/post/cherokee/18-10-21/</guid>
      <description>Patching Holes This post is a continuation of the mini series about restoring my old XJ cherokee. In the previous post I talked about cutting out and welding in a new rocker panel.
Initially the plan for this weekend was to finish welding in the new driver side rocker panel. However, I managed to screw up trimming it to fit and had to order another replacement which wont be in for about a week.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cherokee Build - 10/8/18</title>
      <link>https://EddieAbbondanzio.github.io/post/cherokee/18-10-08/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Oct 2018 17:22:42 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://EddieAbbondanzio.github.io/post/cherokee/18-10-08/</guid>
      <description>Passenger side rocker replacement This post is the second part in my mini-series of restoring my old xj cherokee. If your interested, check out my attempt at saving the rusty roof.
Like most xjs out there, especially those in the rustier parts of the US, the rocker panels needed some love. I never really captured a good before shot of the rust on the passenger side rocker. It was roughly 9&amp;rdquo; in length and about 3&amp;rdquo; wide.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cherokee Build - 9/03/18</title>
      <link>https://EddieAbbondanzio.github.io/post/cherokee/18-09-03/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Sep 2018 12:57:42 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://EddieAbbondanzio.github.io/post/cherokee/18-09-03/</guid>
      <description>Repainting the Cherokee&amp;rsquo;s roof I&amp;rsquo;m a big fan of older vehicles. I just love the simplicity of them and how easy they are to work on them. Plus the cost of parts really can&amp;rsquo;t be beat. Since my civic is far from snow worthy I also own a 2000 Jeep Cherokee. It may not be the prettiest vehicle out there but it&amp;rsquo;s never let me down, and has successfully travelled 20,000 miles in it&amp;rsquo;s first year of owner ship with a couple road trips ranging in the 800-1000 mile range.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>