<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Civic on Eddie Abbondanzio</title>
    <link>https://EddieAbb95.github.io/categories/civic/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Civic on Eddie Abbondanzio</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 Apr 2018 18:04:42 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://EddieAbb95.github.io/categories/civic/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Civic Build - 4/8/18</title>
      <link>https://EddieAbb95.github.io/post/civic/4-8-18-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Apr 2018 18:04:42 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://EddieAbb95.github.io/post/civic/4-8-18-update/</guid>
      <description>New Transmission Mount Installed Progress wise not too much more has been done on the Civic this week. I had to help out my girlfriend put new front brakes + an oil change so I wasn&amp;rsquo;t feeling too motivated after that. My Dad helped out and welded in the new transmission bracket though. It came out pretty awesome and should (hopefully) have no problem mounting up the B swap.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Civic Build - 4/6/18</title>
      <link>https://EddieAbb95.github.io/post/civic/4-6-18-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Apr 2018 16:22:42 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://EddieAbb95.github.io/post/civic/4-6-18-update/</guid>
      <description>Wrapping it up It&amp;rsquo;s funny, you never realize how many things are missing until you try to finish up your project. I spent today going over the motor ensuring I had everything I needed for it. Turns out I was missing quite a few bolts, and some misc small things.
Initially I wanted to work on finishing up the engine bay but with how cold it was outside I decided to focus on the motor instead.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>B-Series Bolt Sizes</title>
      <link>https://EddieAbb95.github.io/post/civic/b-series-bolts/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Apr 2018 15:22:42 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://EddieAbb95.github.io/post/civic/b-series-bolts/</guid>
      <description>Trying to find the size of a missing bolt? I&amp;rsquo;m in the middle of swapping a B20B into my 1993 civic, and I had to buy (just about) every bolt / nut on the engine and transmission since I was missing so many. I also had the pleasure of tracking down all this information from various forums and sources. To try to help any others who are partaking in a similar project I&amp;rsquo;ve compiled a list of what I found below.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Civic Build 4-1-18</title>
      <link>https://EddieAbb95.github.io/post/civic/4-1-18-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2018 15:22:42 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://EddieAbb95.github.io/post/civic/4-1-18-update/</guid>
      <description>I like projects And I&amp;rsquo;m the kind of person that can&amp;rsquo;t leave a car alone. My civic is a 1993 DX hatch that I picked up off a friend of a friend 3 years ago. When I first bought it, it was an automatic and 100% stock. Cut to today and it&amp;rsquo;s totally different, it&amp;rsquo;s gone through rust repair, a paint job, and currently another motor swap. If your interested in it&amp;rsquo;s full history check out my build thread on D-Series.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>