<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>OG XJ Build on Eddie Abbondanzio</title>
    <link>https://eddieabbondanz.io/series/xj-build/</link>
    <description>Recent content in OG XJ Build on Eddie Abbondanzio</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://eddieabbondanz.io/series/xj-build/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Rust Repair Part 22: Getting Jiggy With the XJ and Putting It on a Chassis Table</title>
      <link>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/xj/unibody-rust-repair-part-22/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/xj/unibody-rust-repair-part-22/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve made it pretty far on the metal work for my XJ without a chassis table but once I finish up the driver side I&amp;rsquo;ll need to start replacing the floor and frame rails so the rear suspension needs to come out and that means the XJ won&amp;rsquo;t have any wheels.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LS Swap Part 2: Converting a NP241C Transfer Case For the XJ With a SYE</title>
      <link>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/xj/ls-swap-part-2-transfer-case/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/xj/ls-swap-part-2-transfer-case/</guid>
      <description>There&amp;rsquo;s several options for transfer cases when LS swapping an XJ. Two of the more popular options are running the stock NP231 / NP242 with an adapter so it&amp;rsquo;ll mate up to the GM transmission or use a GM transfer case such as the NP241 that can be adapted to work with the XJ&amp;rsquo;s driveshafts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rust Repair Part 21: Blowing Off the Dust a Year Later AGAIN</title>
      <link>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/xj/unibody-rust-repair-part-21/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/xj/unibody-rust-repair-part-21/</guid>
      <description>Another year has come and gone and the XJ remains in pieces. I truly intended on starting to fix it last time I posted about the XJ but then I impulsively bought a second XJ  and it needed some work of it&amp;rsquo;s own that ended up taking me almost a year to finish.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rust Repair Part 20: Blowing Off the Dust a Year Later</title>
      <link>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/xj/unibody-rust-repair-part-20/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/xj/unibody-rust-repair-part-20/</guid>
      <description>I can&amp;rsquo;t believe it&amp;rsquo;s a been a year since I last worked on the XJ. When I first paused working on the XJ to get my EG hatch back on the road I didn&amp;rsquo;t think it&amp;rsquo;d be for more a few months but sure enough here we are a year later.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LS Swap Part 1: A New Heart for the XJ</title>
      <link>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/xj/ls-swap-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/xj/ls-swap-part-1/</guid>
      <description>For the past year I&amp;rsquo;ve been daydreaming about a 6.0 LQ4 + 4L60E build but after seeing the prices of LQ4s I (the 6.0 tax is real) I decided to go with it&amp;rsquo;s little brother the 5.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rust Repair Part 19: Salvaging What I Can of the Driver Side</title>
      <link>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/xj/unibody-rust-repair-part-19/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/xj/unibody-rust-repair-part-19/</guid>
      <description>There&amp;rsquo;s a lot of rust on the driver side of my XJ, but it&amp;rsquo;s not as bad as the passenger side used to be. Back when I first began on phase 2 of the rust repair, I purposely started on the passenger side as I thought it&amp;rsquo;d be the easier of the two sides, but it turns out that wasn&amp;rsquo;t the case.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rust Repair Part 18: Diving Into the Driver Side and Fixing the Drip Rail</title>
      <link>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/xj/unibody-rust-repair-part-18/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/xj/unibody-rust-repair-part-18/</guid>
      <description>Having finished the passenger side, it was a little daunting looking at the completely untouched driver side knowing I had so much work ahead of me. I was a little worried I&amp;rsquo;d lose my motivation from analysis paralysis on where to start so I decided to dive right into it and start with the roof like I did on the passenger side.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rust Repair Part 17: Finally Finishing the Passenger Quarter Panel</title>
      <link>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/xj/unibody-rust-repair-part-17/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/xj/unibody-rust-repair-part-17/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s taken me roughly 3 times as long as I imagined to finish all the work on the passenger side, but it&amp;rsquo;s been well worth the effort. To recap the past 6 months I&amp;rsquo;ve replaced:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rust Repair Part 16: A New Rear Passenger Inner Wheel Well</title>
      <link>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/xj/unibody-rust-repair-part-16/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/xj/unibody-rust-repair-part-16/</guid>
      <description>Sometimes life does that thing where it gets in the way for awhile. The XJ ended up sitting and collecting dust for a few months due to other priorities eating up my time but I&amp;rsquo;m finally tearing back into it and making progress again.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rust Repair Part 15: Finalizing the 2x6 Rocker</title>
      <link>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/xj/unibody-rust-repair-part-15/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/xj/unibody-rust-repair-part-15/</guid>
      <description>Even though I&amp;rsquo;m making progress it sure feels like the parts pile is getting bigger as each week passes.  
The doors on the left are the old ones and will eventually be scrapped once I remove all the parts I want to salvage off them, but everything else is waiting to be installed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rust Repair Part 14: Welding in the Passenger 2x6 Rocker</title>
      <link>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/xj/unibody-rust-repair-part-14/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/xj/unibody-rust-repair-part-14/</guid>
      <description>In this post we&amp;rsquo;ll continue building out the 2x6 rocker for the passenger side.
 Finishing Up The A Pillar  Before I could weld up the outer rocker I needed to finish the A / B Pillars so I&amp;rsquo;d have something to weld it to.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rust Repair Part 13: Replacing the Passenger Inner Rocker To Prep for 2x6 Rockers</title>
      <link>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/xj/unibody-rust-repair-part-13/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/xj/unibody-rust-repair-part-13/</guid>
      <description>With all this metal laying around it was about time I started putting it to use.  
While the 2x6 rocker mod (aka rock sliders) for XJ isn&amp;rsquo;t uncommon by any means, I&amp;rsquo;m planning on taking a slightly different approach in how I tie them into the unibody.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rust Repair Part 12: Welding in the New Passenger Drip Rail</title>
      <link>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/xj/unibody-rust-repair-part-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/xj/unibody-rust-repair-part-12/</guid>
      <description>My new metal brake finally arrived.  
Before settling on the Woodward Fab Boss 16, I spent several hours researching metal brakes and looked at a ton of different models across various manufacturers such as Baileigh, Tennsmith, Grizzly, JET, Eastwood, and Enco.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rust Repair Part 11: Finishing What I Started</title>
      <link>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/xj/unibody-rust-repair-part-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/xj/unibody-rust-repair-part-11/</guid>
      <description>Just shy of two years ago now, I embarked on the largest rust repair job I&amp;rsquo;ve ever done on my XJ. It took me several months, but I was able to replace the entire rear cargo floor including the crossmembers, gas tank bracing, and unibody frame rails along with welding in rear frame stiffeners over my newly made frame rails.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fabricating a New Rear Bumper</title>
      <link>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/xj/fabricating-a-rear-bumper/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/xj/fabricating-a-rear-bumper/</guid>
      <description>Preface  I&amp;rsquo;ve been driving my Jeep around for almost 6 months now with no rear bumper. I know, I know, not the safest choice but I don&amp;rsquo;t drive far.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Replacing a Saggy Headliner</title>
      <link>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/xj/replacing-a-saggy-headliner/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/xj/replacing-a-saggy-headliner/</guid>
      <description>Delaying the Inevitable  When it comes to my cars, I like to bunch up my repairs / mods into batches where I&amp;rsquo;ll focus on one small sub-category of tasks before moving onto the next.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Installing a Gentex 177 Auto Dimming Rear View Mirror</title>
      <link>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/xj/gentex-177-mirror-install/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/xj/gentex-177-mirror-install/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s hard to explain, but driving a car at night that has an auto dimming rear view mirror is a real treat. It&amp;rsquo;s one of those things that you&amp;rsquo;ll never notice when it&amp;rsquo;s working, but as soon as you don&amp;rsquo;t have it you&amp;rsquo;ll notice its absence immediately.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rust Repair Part 10: The Finishing Touches</title>
      <link>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/xj/unibody-rust-repair-part-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/xj/unibody-rust-repair-part-10/</guid>
      <description>The epoxy primer I used on the underside of my repairs is some pretty good stuff, but I wanted just a hair more protection down there. And after all can you really say you did a rust repair job on your Jeep if bedliner wasn&amp;rsquo;t involved?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rust Repair Part 9: Closing Up The Floor</title>
      <link>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/xj/unibody-rust-repair-part-9/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/xj/unibody-rust-repair-part-9/</guid>
      <description>The least exciting portion of this project by far was closing up the two holes left in the floor directly below where the rear seat goes. I initally cut these holes in the floor way back at the beginning of the project because I needed to remove the original frame rails.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rust Repair Part 8: Welding on Frame Stiffeners</title>
      <link>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/xj/unibody-rust-repair-part-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/xj/unibody-rust-repair-part-8/</guid>
      <description>One of my biggest concerns about my custom fabricated frame rails was the vertical welds joining the frame sections. Vertical welds like those are a big no no when it comes to frames because they&amp;rsquo;re especially prone to failing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rust Repair Part 7: A New Fuel Neck Housing And Making Cut N Fold Panels</title>
      <link>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/xj/unibody-rust-repair-part-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/xj/unibody-rust-repair-part-7/</guid>
      <description>The Fuel Neck Housing  I&amp;rsquo;ve been ignoring the gaping hole around where the fuel neck passes through the interior to travel down towards the gas tank. I had a feeling it&amp;rsquo;d be easy to fix so I never put much thought into it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rust Repair Part 6: Turning A Patch Panel Into A New Cargo Floor Pan</title>
      <link>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/xj/unibody-rust-repair-part-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/xj/unibody-rust-repair-part-6/</guid>
      <description>Building Out The Cargo Floor  I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to try to salvage the original cargo area floor from my Jeep. It had rusted through in several spots, and I kinda chopped it up into several pieces because I only removed bits of it as a time when I was fabricating the new frame rails.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rust Repair Part 5: Designing A Custom Gas Tank Cradle</title>
      <link>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/xj/unibody-rust-repair-part-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/xj/unibody-rust-repair-part-5/</guid>
      <description>Directly below the floor of the XJ in the cargo area sits the gas tank. Tucked tight between the frame rails it rests a mere 1/2&amp;quot; from the floor. The mount for the gas tank is also what braces the floor in the cargo area.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rust Repair Part 4: Hooking Up The Suspension</title>
      <link>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/xj/unibody-rust-repair-part-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/xj/unibody-rust-repair-part-4/</guid>
      <description>With the frame squared away I needed something that I could mount up the suspension to. The only thing holding in the rear axle at this point was the rear driveshaft and the front mounts of the leaf springs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rust Repair Part 3: Déjà Vu Replacing the Driver Frame Rail</title>
      <link>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/xj/unibody-rust-repair-part-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/xj/unibody-rust-repair-part-3/</guid>
      <description>The driver side frame rail was in far worse shape than the passenger side on my XJ. I opted to replace the passenger side first since there&amp;rsquo;s a little less going on on that side.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rust Repair Part 2: Bending a New Passenger Frame Rail</title>
      <link>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/xj/unibody-rust-repair-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/xj/unibody-rust-repair-part-2/</guid>
      <description>Using a metal brake to bend up new frame rails wasn&amp;rsquo;t my plan A. Nor was it plan B. It was actually plan C. I was trying to fix my Jeep on the cheap because this repair wasn&amp;rsquo;t suppose to happen till spring.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rust Repair Part 1: Fabricating A New Rear Crossmember</title>
      <link>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/xj/unibody-rust-repair-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/xj/unibody-rust-repair-part-1/</guid>
      <description>Background  I like to joke and say that anyone else would have sent my XJ to the junkyard.
My Cherokee is rusty, has a laundry list of issues, gets 17 MPG on the good days, and is literally a brick on wheels.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dana 30 Front Axle Rebuild</title>
      <link>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/xj/dana-30-rebuild/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/xj/dana-30-rebuild/</guid>
      <description>The front axle of my Cherokee has been in desperate need of some attention for quite awhile. Just about every component on it was worn to the point of needing to be replaced and the axle housing itself had built up some pretty intense rust.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>XJ Build - 02/03/19</title>
      <link>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/xj/19-02-03/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/xj/19-02-03/</guid>
      <description>The Cherokee strikes again. A couple weeks back when my exhaust snapped just before the catalytic converter I noticed my muffler had a minor leak. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t anything major and wasn&amp;rsquo;t loud so I figured I could probably just run it till spring and deal with it when it was warmer out.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>XJ Build - 01/26/19</title>
      <link>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/xj/19-01-26/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/xj/19-01-26/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve honestly been very lucky with my Jeep. My previous daily driver was a 2009 Subaru Legacy, and while it may have been excellent in the snow it had a very high cost of ownership.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>XJ Build - 10/26/18</title>
      <link>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/xj/18-10-26/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/xj/18-10-26/</guid>
      <description>With winter approaching fast, and my Civic only having summer tires I needed to hurry up and finish the Cherokee. The Civic was also suffering from a stuck open thermostat that ensured the engine temperature never reached operating temp, and my heat was always cold.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>XJ Build - 10/21/18</title>
      <link>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/xj/18-10-21/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/xj/18-10-21/</guid>
      <description>Patching Holes  This post is a continuation of the mini series about restoring my old XJ cherokee. In the previous post I talked about cutting out and welding in a new rocker panel.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>XJ Build - 10/8/18</title>
      <link>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/xj/18-10-08/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/xj/18-10-08/</guid>
      <description>This post is the second part in my mini-series of restoring my old xj cherokee. If your interested, check out my attempt at saving the rusty roof.
 
Like most xjs out there, especially those in the rustier parts of the US, the rocker panels needed some love.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>XJ Build - 9/03/18</title>
      <link>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/xj/18-09-03/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/xj/18-09-03/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m a big fan of older vehicles. I just love the simplicity of them and how easy they are to work on them. Plus the cost of parts really can&amp;rsquo;t be beat.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
