<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Cherokee Build on Eddie Abbondanzio</title>
    <link>https://eddieabbondanz.io/series/cherokee-build/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Cherokee Build on Eddie Abbondanzio</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2019. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 22 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://eddieabbondanz.io/series/cherokee-build/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>XJ - Ass Cancer Rehab Part 5: Designing A Custom Gas Tank Cradle</title>
      <link>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/xj/ass-cancer-rehab-part-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/xj/ass-cancer-rehab-part-5/</guid>
      <description>Directly below the floor of the XJ in the cargo area sits the gas tank. Tucked tight between the frame rails it rests a mere 1/2&amp;quot; from the floor. The mount for the gas tank is also what braces the floor in the cargo area. Well that&amp;rsquo;s how the OEM set up is at least. In my case I had a large gaping hole with nothing there.
Shortly after completing the rear crossmember and realizing how hard fabrication really is I began to dread having to build a new gas tank cradle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>XJ - Ass Cancer Rehab Part 4: Hooking Up The Suspension</title>
      <link>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/xj/ass-cancer-rehab-part-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/xj/ass-cancer-rehab-part-4/</guid>
      <description>With the frame squared away I needed something that I could mount up the suspension to. The only thing holding in the rear axle at this point was the rear driveshaft and the front mounts of the leaf springs. The OEM shock crossmember is nothing more than 2 pieces of 16ga steel stamped together and mine was far too rusted to save.
I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to see if I could hunt down an OEM replacement because it seems like just about every part is discontinued nowadays, thanks Mopar.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>XJ - Ass Cancer Rehab Part 3: Déjà Vu Replacing the Driver Frame Rail</title>
      <link>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/xj/ass-cancer-rehab-part-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/xj/ass-cancer-rehab-part-3/</guid>
      <description>The driver side frame rail was in far worse shape than the passenger side on my XJ. I opted to replace the passenger side first since there&amp;rsquo;s a little less going on on that side. On the driver side the fuel neck hoses pass through the frame, and all of the fuel lines, brake lines, and vacuum lines run parallel down the frame rail.
I figured once I had a little experience under my belt, the driver side would be a lot easier to manage.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>XJ - Ass Cancer Rehab Part 2: Bending a New Passenger Frame Rail</title>
      <link>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/xj/ass-cancer-rehab-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/xj/ass-cancer-rehab-part-2/</guid>
      <description>Using a metal brake to bend up new frame rails wasn&amp;rsquo;t my plan A. Nor was it plan B. It was actually plan C. I was trying to fix my Jeep on the cheap because this repair wasn&amp;rsquo;t suppose to happen till spring. That meant no buying extra tools and trying to make do with what I had.
Plan A The first plan was to cut up some spare 2x2 steel tubing for the 90 degree bends and then weld them with pieces of sheet metal to create new frame sections.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>XJ - Ass Cancer Rehab Part 1: A New Rear Crossmember</title>
      <link>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/xj/ass-cancer-rehab-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/xj/ass-cancer-rehab-part-1/</guid>
      <description>Background I like to joke and say that anyone else would have sent my XJ to the junkyard.
Somedays if I&amp;rsquo;m in an especially sour mood from working on it, I&amp;rsquo;ll joke and say that anyone smart would have sent my XJ to the junkyard.
My Cherokee is rusty, has a laundry list of issues, gets 17 MPG on the good days, and is literally a brick on wheels. But I love it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>XJ Build - 02/03/19</title>
      <link>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/xj/19-02-03/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Feb 2019 17:28:42 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/xj/19-02-03/</guid>
      <description>The Cherokee strikes again. A couple weeks back when my exhaust snapped just before the catalytic converter I noticed my muffler had a minor leak. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t anything major and wasn&amp;rsquo;t loud so I figured I could probably just run it till spring and deal with it when it was warmer out.
The Jeep had other plans though as the leak grew in size, and became extremely obnoxious. Due to the internals of the muffler rusting and coming loose, the muffler developed a horrendous rattle that sounded like a trumpet blasting a low note when at 2300RPM.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>XJ Build - 01/26/19</title>
      <link>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/xj/19-01-26/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Jan 2019 16:51:42 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/xj/19-01-26/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve honestly been very lucky with my Jeep. My previous daily driver was a 2009 Subaru Legacy, and while it may have been excellent in the snow it had a very high cost of ownership. I figured out that it was costing me on average $100 in maintenance per 1000 miles travelled. It may sound silly to have sold the Subaru and bought a Jeep that was 9 years older but I have zero regrets doing so.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>XJ Build - 10/26/18</title>
      <link>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/xj/18-10-26/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Oct 2018 16:51:42 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/xj/18-10-26/</guid>
      <description>Finishing Up With winter approaching fast, and my Civic only having summer tires I needed to hurry up and finish the Cherokee. The Civic was also suffering from a stuck open thermostat that ensured the engine temperature never reached operating temp, and my heat was always cold.
The funny thing is, when I was preparing to drop the B20B engine into the Civic I clearly remember thinking how pointless it would be to replace the thermostat.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>XJ Build - 10/21/18</title>
      <link>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/xj/18-10-21/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Oct 2018 16:51:42 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/xj/18-10-21/</guid>
      <description>Patching Holes This post is a continuation of the mini series about restoring my old XJ cherokee. In the previous post I talked about cutting out and welding in a new rocker panel.
Initially the plan for this weekend was to finish welding in the new driver side rocker panel. However, I managed to screw up trimming it to fit and had to order another replacement which wont be in for about a week.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>XJ Build - 10/8/18</title>
      <link>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/xj/18-10-08/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Oct 2018 17:22:42 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/xj/18-10-08/</guid>
      <description>Passenger side rocker replacement This post is the second part in my mini-series of restoring my old xj cherokee. If your interested, check out my attempt at saving the rusty roof.
Like most xjs out there, especially those in the rustier parts of the US, the rocker panels needed some love. I never really captured a good before shot of the rust on the passenger side rocker. It was roughly 9&amp;quot; in length and about 3&amp;quot; wide.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>XJ Build - 9/03/18</title>
      <link>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/xj/18-09-03/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Sep 2018 12:57:42 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/xj/18-09-03/</guid>
      <description>Repainting the Cherokee&amp;rsquo;s roof I&amp;rsquo;m a big fan of older vehicles. I just love the simplicity of them and how easy they are to work on them. Plus the cost of parts really can&amp;rsquo;t be beat. Since my civic is far from snow worthy I also own a 2000 Jeep Cherokee. It may not be the prettiest vehicle out there but it&amp;rsquo;s never let me down, and has successfully travelled 20,000 miles in it&amp;rsquo;s first year of owner ship with a couple road trips ranging in the 800-1000 mile range.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
