<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Meta on Eddie Abbondanzio</title>
    <link>https://eddieabbondanz.io/categories/meta/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Meta on Eddie Abbondanzio</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2019. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Oct 2018 15:22:42 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://eddieabbondanz.io/categories/meta/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>My Work Station 2.0</title>
      <link>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/misc/desk2-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Oct 2018 15:22:42 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/misc/desk2-0/</guid>
      <description>Going all out This post is a successor to my first attempt at building a standing desk. Back during college when I built my first desk I didn&amp;rsquo;t have much of a budget since it was a spur of the moment decision. Because of this the solution I came up with ended up being a permanent standing desk built using misc. parts from Lowe&amp;rsquo;s. Ever since graduating from college however, I&amp;rsquo;ve found it less than thrilling to come home and stand at my desk after standing all day at work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Work Station</title>
      <link>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/misc/desk/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2018 15:22:42 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/misc/desk/</guid>
      <description>My Budget Build At my work, I&amp;rsquo;m fortunate enough to have one of those adjustable desks that allow for you to stand or sit while you work. Since I almost always have it in the standing mode I decided to build my own standing desk at home. However I&amp;rsquo;m on a college student budget, and don&amp;rsquo;t want to spend an arm and a leg right now. In the end I came up with this solution that&amp;rsquo;s left me pretty happy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New site, who this?</title>
      <link>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/misc/first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Mar 2018 10:06:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eddieabbondanz.io/post/misc/first-post/</guid>
      <description>Welcome! If your reading this, it means you&amp;rsquo;ve found my new website. It&amp;rsquo;s still in it&amp;rsquo;s early stages so it may seem quite primitive. It&amp;rsquo;s powered via Hugo, and while I may have a decent grasp of HTML/CSS/JS, Go is a whole new concept.
In the following weeks I&amp;rsquo;ll work on dialing things in and at the same time post progresss about my various projects I&amp;rsquo;m working on.
What is this blog about?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>